The Minnesota Vikings coming into the
2026 NFL draft had needs at Dline,
Oline, safety, cornerback, and wide
receiver. In day one and two of the NFL
draft, they addressed most of their
needs already. You went out and got two
DTackles, Caleb Banks and Dominique
Orange. On a Caleb Banks pick, you know,
a lot of people had him as a 60th player
grade, but go get your guy. If there's a
guy your scouts have went out and they
saw him in person, they watched a ton of
film on him. Uh, this is a guy that
doesn't have a ton of stats when you
look at him, but team first guy,
unselfish guy, project, big body type,
space eater. That's the things you need
in a three- four defense. You might not
need a superstar right away. You just
need a guy that can play within your
scheme. And I think this is what Brian
Flores renown did with with Caleb Banks.
You got Jake Golday, linebacker out of
Cincinnati. He's long. He's versatile.
He was a former defensive end. So, he
understands setting the edge. He
understands contain. You put him off
ball, and that's what Cincinnati did.
This is a guy that if he probably plays
off ball, rush outside linebacker his
entire career, he's probably a first
round pick, but he's learning the
position and he does it really well. He
can play in the A gap, the B gap, the C
gap. You see him lined up in the wide
nine. You see him lined up uh back in
the in a true like three, four type of
look where he's one of the middle, the
mic or the mole linebackers and he
dissects and reads really well coming
downhill, you know, getting through
lanes, getting skinny, but also off the
edge rushing the quarterback. He has
that violent hand. Knock the guy's arms
down, get to the quarterback quick,
swipe and try to get a strip sack. So,
he looks like he looks the part. And uh
when I when I look at him, he's wearing
number 11, of course, so it reminds me a
little bit of Anthony Bar. Um but you
look at Caleb Tyranninan, big 67, 323
pound offensive tackle. Truly
prototypical. You think about backing up
Brian O'Neal and Christian Darasaw with
injuries. This is a guy that can
potentially come in and be a starter if
one of your guys is hurt or not fully
ready to go or they just need a veteran
couple days off. You have a kid now in
Caleb Tieran and they could be the
future offensive tackle for this team.
Uh but then Jacobe Thomas, that's the
one that I really like out of Miami.
Middle Tennessee State for three years,
went on to Tennessee for 13 games and
then Miami uh playing all the way
through the playoffs. But one game that
really stood out to me was against
Florida. Now, we know Miami vers is a
big time game anyway, but big- time
players make big times, big- time plays
in big time games. And that's what this
kid did. You saw him deep safety, come
up kind of like a hairy hitman, be on
the edge, quake off the edge, bend the
corner, get to the quarterback, gets a
sack. Then you see him come from depth,
get to linebacker level. You don't know
if he's going to be the linebacker level
guy. You don't know if he's going to
drop back. And he shoots the gap and
breaks up a a run play in the back
field. This is a kid that Brian Flores
really can use, can play on the back
end, disguises well, can blitz, and I
think a blitzing safety, that's Brian
Flores's defense all day, every day. And
a guy that's willing to put his nose in
there. You see him with some big hits.
He hit the quarterback, I think it was
from USF, uh, broke up, had a fumble,
but he put his helmet right on the ball,
put his face mask on the ball. That's
how you make a tackle. And he's not
afraid to come down. He'll make a
tackle. I think 49 tackles in the
regular season, four interceptions. He's
again, this is more like that Caleb
Binham type of pick. Can come in and can
be a future starter and big- time player
for this defense. Well, the Vikings
definitely had a busy second day of the
draft, nabbing four picks in the second
and third round. Let's run through them
real quickly and see what they bring to
this Minnesota Vikings team. First of,
Jake Gold, linebacker, University of
Cincinnati. start his life as a
defensive lineman at at Central
Arkansas, worked his way, gets to
Cincinnati, becomes an outside
linebacker, mostly in space is where
you're going to see him, but you will
see him as a mic or a will linebacker
behind the line of scrimmage where I
actually think he excels. Does a great
job of reading guards, gets downhill,
he's physical at the point. I think he
can play at any inside or outside
position in this Brian Flores scheme.
So, it's going to be very interesting to
see where this kid ends up, but he has
all the physical traits. Very tall, very
durable, didn't miss a game his last two
seasons of his college career. Fast
forward to the third round with the 82nd
pick overall. The Minnesota Vikings
select Dominique Orange. Okay, Big
Citrus is this kid's nickname. 6'2,
lbs of man. a 450 pound bench press and
a 600 pound squat in college. An
absolute beast. Strong, exactly what you
need in the middle to plug up the run.
Very good north and south. Physical,
plays with a lot of leverage. He'll work
on the pass rush skills, but for now, he
is going to be big inside for stopping
the run. The next pick, 97th overall in
the third round, the Minnesota Vikings
select Caleb Tieran, offensive lineman,
tackle from Northwestern. He started
there for three and a half years. Didn't
miss a single game. Decided to play in
the bowl game. People criticize him for
having the short arms, but he's a big
guy. He's 6'8.
6'8", 330 lbs. He can play, I think,
anywhere across the board except for
maybe center. guard may ultimately be
where he ends up, but consider him a
great swing guy and a great, let's call
him a sixth man for this offense. So,
you could put him at either tackle
because he played both tackles at some
point in college. Has maybe the
flexibility to move the guard. We'll
see. But a great depth piece for this
offensive line. And finally, a guy I
might be most excited about is Jacobe
Thomas, safety from the University of
Miami. Now, why would I be most excited
about this safety? Because Jacobe Thomas
knows how to blitz and he's absolutely
physical. His four five speed at the
combine might have scared some people
away, but let me tell you something.
When you look at this kid's numbers
throughout his college career,
especially his final year at the
University of Miami, 76 tackles, four
tackles for loss, three and a half
sacks. That's what I'm thinking about.
You want a safety that can blitz in this
defense. And I really think that Jacobe
Thomas is is your guy. Two force
fumbles, 11 passes defensed, and five
total interceptions. So, he was
definitely productive, definitely
aggressive, definitely around the
football. Sounds like a guy that would
fit in a Brian Flores scheme. So, let's
stay tuned for rounds four through
seven.